done.lu 2019-08-28

# Privacy Policy - Done here is how we treat all the data we collect.

**Privacy Policy**

We assure you that we attach great importance to the protection of your personal data. We invite you to review this privacy policy. You will find the nature of the personal data we collect about you, the reasons why we collect them, how long they are kept and how you can exercise your rights in this regard.

**Article 1 – Liability**  
Done SARL, whose registered office is located at 60, rue de Reckange, L-3943 Mondercange, Grand Duchy of Luxembourg, registered for VAT under number LU27317130 (hereinafter “Done SARL”, “we”, “our”, “us”) is the controller. In other words, Done SARL determines the purpose and means of processing personal data.

**Article 2 – Personal Data**  
When you use our services and applications, we may obtain personal data about you. In particular in the following cases:

  * you are visiting our website (see also our “cookie policy”);
  * you register on our website, on a social media platform or in a point of sale, for example when you place an order, when you buy a product from the Done SARL range, when you make a request for a spare part or repair or when you contact our customer service;
  * you register for our contests or promotional actions.

We may obtain the following personal data about you:

  * your customer data (for example, surname, first name, username, password for your Done SARL account, delivery address, e-mail address, telephone number, billing data, purchase history, payment methods used, contact history with customer service);
  * other personal data, such as your username on a social media, your date of birth or the data you provide to us when you register for a contest or promotional action.

**Article 3 – Purposes of the processing operation**

**General purposes**

Done SARL will use your personal data for the following general purposes:

  * **In order to be able to provide you with the service you have requested**

We collect certain personal data about you in order to be able to provide you with the service you have requested (for example, your delivery address as part of a delivery, your billing data in order to be able to invoice you correctly or the profile data of your Done SARL account with regard to your use of our website).

  * **In order to meet certain legal obligations**

In some cases, we are required by law to collect and retain certain personal data about you. Thus, in certain circumstances, we are legally obliged to issue an invoice and keep it (for example in the case of a distance sale). Therefore, we will ask you to provide us with your billing information.

In addition, it is possible in rare cases that Done SARL  
may be forced to disclose your personal data following a court decision or in order to comply with mandatory legislation or regulations. Done SARL will always try to inform you, unless this is not possible due to legal obligations.

  * **In order to detect and combat fraud and infringements**

We carry out various controls in the context of detecting and combating fraud and breaches. This way, we can determine if a payment has been accepted before delivering a product to the customer.  
In addition, our offices and points of sale are equipped with a camera surveillance system to ensure the safety of people and goods. The presence of a camera surveillance system is always reported at the entrance to our offices or points of sale.

  * **In order to improve our services and processes**

We evaluate our services and processes based on your contacts with our employees. In order to improve these services and processes, we also carry out trend analyses based on anonymised and aggregated data.

**Direct marketing and prospecting**  
If you have given us permission, we have the right to use your data for prospecting purposes. You may withdraw this authorisation at any time, without stating reasons and free of charge, for example by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of each promotional e-mail or by contacting Done SARL by e-mail at you@done.lu or by post (Attention: Done SARL- Data Protection Officer, 1, rue Pletzer L-8080 Bertrange).

**Article 4 – Transfer to third parties**  
Done SARL undertakes not to sell, rent or distribute your personal data or make them available to third parties for commercial purposes, except in the cases mentioned above or with your prior consent.

In the event of a reorganization or transfer – in whole or in part – of Done SARL  
‘s activities, your data may then be transmitted to other entities or third parties through which Done SARL’s operational activities will then be carried out, in whole or in part. We will try to inform you in advance.

**Article 5 – Duration of processing**  
We do not keep your personal data for longer than necessary to achieve the purpose for which we collect them. Their storage period may vary depending on the purpose for which we intend them. For example, Done SARL is subject to the legal obligation to keep invoices issued for 10 years. In addition, we believe that it is legally necessary to retain certain data as evidence in the event of a dispute for a maximum period of 10 years.

Unless a longer storage period is legally required, we delete or anonymize your data 10 years after your last contact with Done SARL.

**Article 6 – Your rights and their exercise**

  * **Access rights**

You have the right at any time and free of charge to be informed of the personal data we process about you and to obtain additional information on this subject.

  * **Right of rectification, deletion and limitation of processing**

You are free toshare or not your personal data with Done SARL. In addition, you have the right to ask us to correct or complete your personal data. You also have the right to request the deletion of this data. In this case, you must take into account the fact that some products and services can no longer be offered to you. Thus, in the event of loss of your proof of purchase, we will no longer be able to determine whether the legal warranty period has expired or not.  
You may also request that the processing of your personal data be limited.

  * **Right of opposition**

You have a right to object to the processing of your personal data for serious and legitimate reasons.  
You also have the right to object to the use of your personal data for prospecting purposes. In such a case, it is not necessary for you to justify your request. To do so, click on the link at the bottom of our promotional emails or contact us at you@done.lu or by post (Attention: Done SARL- Data Protection Officer, 1, rue Pletzer L-8080 Bertrange).

  * **Right to free data portability**

You have the right to request that your personal data that we process be obtained in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format and/or transferred to another controller.

  * **Right to withdraw your authorization**

Provided that the processing is subject to your prior authorisation, you have the right to withdraw this authorisation. To do so, click on the link at the bottom of our promotional emails or contact us by email at you@done.lu or by post (Attention: Done SARL- Data Protection Officer, 1, rue Pletzer L-8080 Bertrange).

  * **Exercise of your rights**

You can also exercise your rights in writing through us, by contacting us by post (Attention: Done SARL- Data Protection Officer, 1, rue Pletzer L-8080 Bertrange) or by e-mail (you@done.lu). If you exercise your rights in writing, we ask you to attach a copy of the front of your identity card to your request. We will only use this copy for the purpose of verifying your identity.

**Article 7 – Automated Decision Making and Profiling**  
In principle, we will not use your personal data for profiling or automated decision-making purposes.

We may maintain an individual profile about you, for the sole purpose of serving you better by providing you with personalized products and offers.

**Article 8 – Right to file a complaint**  
If you wish to file a complaint about the way we process your personal data, you may at any time contact our Data Protection Officer by e-mail at you@done.lu. We will do our best to solve your problem.  
You can also file a complaint with the Luxembourg Commission for the Protection of Privacy: Commission nationale pour la protection des données, avenue du Rock’n’Roll, L-4361 Esch-sur-Alzette, Tel: +352 26 10 60 1, Fax: +352 26 10 60 29.

**Article 9 – Security and confidentiality**  
We have put in place various technically and organisationally appropriate security mechanisms to prevent the destruction, loss, alteration or modification of collected personal data as well as unauthorised access to such data, their erroneous communication to third parties or their submission to any other form of unauthorised processing.  
Done SARL cannot under any circumstances be held liable for any damage – direct or indirect – resulting from the misuse or unauthorised use of your personal data by a third party.  
We would also like to remind you that you are solely responsible for the use of the website from your computer, your IP address and using your identifiers as well as for the confidentiality of this data. We recommend that you take all necessary preventive security measures, including preventing unauthorized access to your user name and password.

**Article 10 – Access by third parties**  
We do not share your personal data with third parties for commercial purposes.  
In order to be able to process your personal data, we make this data accessible to our employees and to companies we have mandated. We guarantee an equivalent level of protection by subjecting these companies to enforceable contractual obligations.

**Article 11 – Contact**  
Feel free to send us any questions you may have about our privacy policy in one of the following ways:

  * by e-mail: you@done.lu
  * by post: To the attention of Done SARL- Data Protection Officer, 1, rue Pletzer L-8080 Bertrange
